Burhan Tuerker

Bursa, TURKEY 16800 +90 (536) 517 18 04 burhan.tuerker@gmail.com

PROFILE

I have experience with many different tools/languages, including microcontroller and computer graphics programming. I am primarily interested in enterprise web applications, and greatly value writing well structured, highly maintainable code. I'm always challenging myself to expand my skill set as I become a software craftsman.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Javascript (ES5/ES6), React, Bootstrap, SQL

EXPERIENCE

Remote, Support Engineer, Microverse Inc. — August 2019-October 2019

- Experienced asynchronous remote workflow in multiple time zones.
- Assisted students with questions regarding troublesome algorithms and data structures by analyzing both the Microverse curriculum and the student's individual knowledge.
- Created 20+ unique guideline articles on topics in algorithm design and analysis, which doubled student solve rates.

Intern, Azimech Software R&D — September 2018-October 2018

- Experimented with microservices architecture by implementing fully isolated services with three different languages and database providers.
- Used .NET core/MSSQL, Spring Boot/MySQL, and Express.js/MongoDB development stacks to provide multi-language CRUD intensive RESTful endpoints.
- Used Netflix's open source cloud solutions to establish service-to-service communication.
- Composed each application to run as a single application with docker.

Intern, Piton Software R&D — May 2018-July 2018

- Full-stack development using Node, Express, Angular, and MongoDB.
- Researched and documented comparisons between non-blocking & blocking architecture with code examples and analogies.
- Independently led the back-end role in a project for managing IoT devices from a web application, which used RESTful architecture to provide clean endpoints to the front-end team.
- Implemented a side project at the request of the supervisor engineer which reported incidents from defined services by making HTTP calls at specific intervals.

EDUCATION

Remote, Microverse Inc. - January 2019-August 2019

- Interacted with students from all around the world.
- Used Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, and Redux.
- Spent 100+ hours on core data structures & algorithms.
- Built 20+ projects with a remote-first pair-programming approach.

Dumlupinar University, BSc. CSE - 2013-2018

AWARDS

Contest, Hackathones 2018 — 2nd place

- Presented a completely working back-end service and mobile application for a hackathon with the theme of "Smart Cities."